we're good to go and now welcome to
brunch
idea cafe for projects today we are
discussing how we will market our
projects whether currently or in the
future depending on what kind of project
it is so in an idea cafe we all take up
to five minutes to answer the question
and then we have an open discussion for
the remainder so if I would like to
start for themselves in their project
and then we can discuss marketing in
general and if anyone wants to join in
you can follow the link in the stream
yard link on the Facebook group I can go
ahead and start alright so for reason
score I don't know I've done I've
created several ideas so I haven't
tested out in these marketing ideas but
one is that just for people that don't
know it's it helps people kind of make
decisions so we produce kind of an
argument map of the pros and cons of a
contentious issue that people are
struggling with so in theory if I'm
sharing that idea it should get shared
quite a bit in social media being a
contentious issue unless it's just
boring to see everything done correctly
which is possible although you can also
kind of Stoke some interaction by you
know the the debates gonna go back and
forth a couple times so if you just say
hey so we have evidence of X and then
all the people that are on the other
side of the debate would you know if
they kind of agree that people will tend
to share if they disagree if it they'll
come and interact so it's kind of a
win-win in in that case so I'm hoping
there's natural morality to the product
but then outside of that yeah I think
will be I'll be looking for people that
volunteer to that really you know there
are some detail-oriented people that
like solving puzzles and hopefully I can
find some of them to work on putting the
content in so I'm hoping there will be a
natural virality
I guess that's about it I've run a
couple more ideas but none of them seem
to work out so I think that's where I'm
stuck so that's it for a reason score
collection sure so they were marketing
to me means a lot of different things as
I'm sure it does to a lot of people some
of the main ones which some of them get
a bit difficult for something is early
stage as wiki election where step one is
to sort of identify the market and
figure out what needs are actually
meeting and you know who you're you're
your target audience is that gets kind
of difficult if you're trying to build
the audience so that you can ask the
questions to go further in in planning
but still trying to go ahead so in this
case it's kind of doing it all at once
which is a bit awkward so in this case
the identifiable audience is kind of
like everyone who votes but the more
specific ones are people who are
actually sort of undecided and actually
want to go and do more research which is
not everyone and then your steps are you
know to figure out how you want to talk
to them and then sort of whip within the
organization having some goal for how
those conversations end up which you
know is them signing up for something
then buying something if that were a if
you know it's a company to have
something to sell which in this case the
election does not so the difficult thing
there again is trying to get people
interested in a concept that's vague
enough to sort of be interesting
theoretically but we don't actually have
anything to show because there hasn't
been enough work done yet because
there's no one to talk to so the
approach that I actually want to take is
to sort of do this is to go out there
and talk about it where necessary to
start building up the audience to kind
of take a stab at it myself
or you know with the few people that I
am in touch with now to use that to
build out the actual sort of first
version of the prototype just so there's
something to show so there's something
to to start from you know because they
say you can't edit a blank page sort of
going on the concept of that which is
common in writing I don't
it's terribly common in software so it's
a bit weird and then for the outcome so
we have the like it's everyone going to
be talking through channels to use one
flood what like this
and then through a collection itself
it'll end up having channels on no he's
booked and Twitter and patreon and all
the normal places and one of the first
sort of things that I think people might
be interested in is if I can get that
early prototype online to set up a
version for like the fictional universe
or all the fictional universes where you
can actually go and sort of use the same
tools to capture the history and sort of
discuss fictional characters and that I
think in itself can you know might prove
interesting for some people hey hey
Shiloh but I think it also proves as
sort of uh testing grounds for the
concept of having a conversation trying
to sort of summarize what someone has
has done but in the you know fictional
universes
some people get pretty at you know
adamantly four against a character or an
idea so it actually does have a bit of
that or it might have a bit of that
heated discussion element that you'd
actually want something like this to
really prove it so I guess the long
story short is using typical channels
like Facebook and Twitter and stuff like
that you know talk to the general public
and hopefully get a few people
interested and then as well people are
interested involved in in the planning
process and sort of access to the
various prototypes and I just remembered
a few things for reason score so we can
either come back later after everyone
else has a turn during the open
discussion you can absolutely at it if
either of you want to want to share your
answer to how you want to mark it or how
you're going to or are marketing your
project then you can go ahead or I can
go cuz I have yet to go that's all oh I
guess my goal is to have an art show or
some sort of collaborative art
installation type thing to introduce the
and then share other people's idea there
as well as my heart
as for myself I was going to tell
everyone everywhere and hope goes viral
no other plans for marketing all right I
think so strangely that is a somewhat I
think that is all of our marketing
strategy because of the fact that it's
world-changing right so anytime you have
something that's actually helping the
worldly hope that it would you go viral
on its own merit but that is a lot I
know I have a difficulty marketing and
if you're not willing to pay for game a
marketing we're not able to pay for game
a marketing on Twitter on Facebook then
the algorithm is designed against it so
for me and my project solution raising
I'm doing what I can which is just going
live on YouTube showcasing them and
hoping that that draws people in to want
to participate and then figure out from
there how we create a process that
people can get involved in on zoom' and
then together we'll figure out how to
bring more people in but the more that
people are actually involved in creating
the solutions themselves that they are
also the marketing strategy that they
are the ones who go on to say hey this
process is fun or you know I know people
who want to be involved in this process
and so the idea is that it goes viral
most people people enjoy the process of
having the conversation and in invite
their friends but it will grow very very
slowly as every one rights friend so
that is what I am doing both nothing and
just allow people viral so we can have
an open conversation as to more of what
recent score is doing and more anything
else that that comes up yeah so I can
jump back in if no one else is burning
to continue the conversation so I
actually I forgot this one idea had four
walls actually to do a game show format
so you haven't you know it's got a lot
like a lot of debate shows except this
one has an actual scoring system so
there be a scoreboard and now also
there's a possibility that you might
actually
get points for strengthening your
opponent's argument it's not been taught
I've quite decided but it may be just
who has the better you know bringing in
facts and stuff like that and even
though if someone figures it out they'll
realize that they get points regardless
of who the points go to so all right
that'd be interesting I mean they'll
come on within our own side and bias so
it'd be hard to do so it's like you get
points and you win for just being the
best at figuring out what's true or not
right and then the outcome is something
that's hopefully more true so if you sit
if you come into it thinking a certain
thing and you change your mind halfway
through and build the evidence for the
other side you can still win if you do
that correctly yeah I got a lot
I'd be fun and then you know could do
live like Q&A show with experts and
stuff like that based on the topics that
we're doing and then have someone kind
of filling in the the reason score
system live which would be hard I'd have
to get someone who's really good at
typing I can do that myself
the other thing is chronic creating
explainer videos like Fox and cup other
other things do more it's the data and
then explain my concern about that is
because the data will kind of change
often or be afraid that the video would
be out of date but I don't know but
that's a possible thing and then you
know also do crowdfunding I thought of
having like doing GoFundMe but have won
one funding tool for one side of the
argument and one for the other so have
to crowd funds going on at the same time
and then people were trying to get more
money into their side although it
doesn't really matter on who's gonna
kind of what sides gonna get the thing
but that that's kind of rival risk but
it's one things I've been thinking about
and and even though it starts off rival
wrists in the end it becomes antivirus
hopefully but yeah so those are some of
the other ideas I thought of and then I
drew I don't know if you mentioned your
videos that
like Saturday and stuff like that in
your description but that's all I also
consider that kind of marketing true
yeah that I mean technically I'm lumping
that into like the multi-channel
approach right so Twitter will be doing
its own thing in Facebook and that's
sort of on YouTube and Facebook but true
yeah that is and that's a part of the
reason why I'm doing it is to just have
content because I think people now if
you go to like a website or you're
trying to do some research and you go to
the website and everything is a year and
a half old you're like oh they stopped
doing it right supposed to no they're
just busy doing other stuff with love
love love it's still going it's to give
people all that you cans to say oh
they're definitely still doing it they
posted two weeks ago cool now your
comment unlike the it being rival race
and maybe changing Tanabe ties into
something that I wanted to bring up from
what Jubilee said which is game a
marketing I'm interested to hear what
what elements of marketing people think
are game a and like you know things that
means in theory should stop doing or at
least start to like move away from happy
under says well I mainly just meant
paying for it and if your project is
game B and you have funds paying for it
there's nothing wrong with it it's how
you get eyeballs on it but also if you
have to eat already socially if there
isn't money coming in and all you're
doing is eyeballs on it it's like it's
no longer as easy to go viral without
paying for it and so that is what I
meant
under and then just the word marketing
is kind of has the connotation of when I
think about viral you generally don't
pay for it
companies try to pay for it and they
fail and then something happens
organically that's what actually goes
viral in my experience yeah I can't
think except for the occasional like you
know there's a video that goes viral and
then you found out that it was like a
guerilla marketing campaign from someone
but that seems to be like you know one
percent of videos we are like oh me that
was some company being clever yeah even
even experts that work on it a long time
cannot consistently make something go
viral yeah one thing to go viral
that's awesome like that you know okay a
career maker for some people if it goes
true the viral yeah consist the
kind of repeatable consistent processes
if you can get a kind of a landing page
that entices people and then you can do
the kind of the game a and pay for
Facebook or Google Ads but yeah for that
you kind of need a revenue model the
only other thing that that consistently
can get people is kind of content
marketing building blog posts and videos
right right is the interesting thing
even in the game a world advertised like
the things that come into advertising
are kind of like the worst ones even
they know like it's not great if I had
to pay for an ad for someone to come in
and see it they aren't as engaged either
it's not organic there's a whole bunch
of problems with that their ideal
scenario is viral is organic is a
referral is like stuff that game B
projects would also really want and so
that is something that I mean you
probably hear me say over the course of
a lot of these videos is to not throw
the baby out with the bathwater as these
things right marketing is a crap ton of
research from really to skilled people
on how humans make decisions
full-stop right and so thank you so much
how much for our game B projects do we
want to like I don't necessarily think
people paid the whole thing for it to go
viral but they definitely start the
payment right they definitely are like
okay we're gonna get the first hundred
likes the first hundred because people
are more likely to share it when it's
already gone viral right people are
already like closing other already
standing in line they pay people to
stand in line so you think it's it's
it's under so people want demands and
then but for people to actually stand
behind you there has to be something
enticing and it's the same where to get
any eyeballs is even certain but once
you have them it's it's easier to get
them organically yeah like a company
will pay for the first you know a
thousand followers on their page so they
have a thousand followers with people
who don't feel like they're their third
follower why am i bothering yeah which
that's an option to sort of fast-track
or in a lot of cases those are like I
don't want to say blackhat but almost
blackhat marketing like if you buy
followers the debt that that's like 2002
blackhat
like you really don't know what what
we're doing now if you're buying
followers did game a or not like it's
just not good but it's probably still
works sometimes to get you to a hundred
or a thousand or whatever but you can't
really scale it to go truly viral it
almost always has to be you have to have
done something right you have to have
hit that right moment that right vein
and don't get me wrong
tons of companies try they spend
millions of dollars across all of them
and marketing teams trying to get
something to go viral and it almost
always fails and then it's you know
somebody in you know their basement make
some funny video and that's the one that
actually goes viral because they just
hit the right moments showed up hit the
right people and that got the actual
algorithm going along that you're it to
more and more people and they they like
that as well there's a lot to be said
about how big a part lock place in
something going viral and it needs to be
just the right combination of the right
time right place right video right type
of whatever and yeah it's hard but if it
goes viral by itself I think shows that
yourself doing something right probably
hopefully it's even painful followers at
the initial stage there's not
necessarily black luck to me is when
you're selling something that you know
is not true like you know the old school
of creating demand for something that
you know is crap so but you want to sell
it anyway because you want profit but to
kick start a campaign it might be okay
if we are doing a good thing
hello sorry doing a good thing
and it might also be that the thing you
are doing this the renew a very mmm not
controversial but it's too modern for
people to just go yeah that's awesome
and we are going to share it because we
see
it's awesome sometimes people need time
to figure out yeah this actually makes
sense this is good so I'll share it but
initially you know some ideas of times
so that's when you need some know
something to kick-start yeah and I agree
it's not necessary blackhat maybe it's
like grey hat or just like just not not
recommended in most cases but it can be
a burka and if people don't notice and
if you you know don't try to get to a
million and you're just trying to like
get started mmhmm yeah I don't think
it's necessarily unethical but it's just
like maybe not the best approach but if
that's your only option then go for it
feel like although this is very much
idea cafe for projects and we're
bringing our own individual projects to
it that this is the kind of thing that
together Tech has to solve our together
because solving it for each individual
project putting your life's work putting
something that can save the world into
something and then hoping it goes viral
hoping it's the right message doesn't
work like this it's like what we need
are the people the eyeballs on it I want
I don't want to trick people into come
you know I want people who are truly
gonna benefit out of what I'm offering
to come and participate and I think that
is what is the same for all game view
projects so having the ability to get
the word out there to people who want
that information is a project in and of
itself that is something we can solve
together but that's not with this but
this conversation is but just wanted to
mention that game a game B needs to
figure out marketing and it will game a
can't compete with that once it does it
- oh no I think one of the challenges
we're gonna have is that skill set is
super and demanding game a and they're
willing to pay big bucks for it so for
the you know foreseeable future game a
projects like I think most of the people
who are involved in game B projects and
in like the game B space are kind of the
like you know moderately tech year or
more so like sort of product focused
talking to
the community I see a lot of seeing
skillsets very few marketers because
they're super busy and be gaming world
they're you know in demand they're being
hunted down that's what I mean is that
if I wanted somebody to market solution
raising then I would want to find a
marketer who has expertise but if what
we want is the right eyeballs on the
project that's more of together Tech's
umbrella of we need overall people so
they can find what's relevant to them
which is very different than a marketer
who's about selling you something versus
actually it's like a researcher is very
different than a marketer and it's
basically we need to do the collective
research together what do we care about
in a product and service and company and
do we have access that information and
then once that's collected it doesn't
matter what you say your product is it
matters is it actually deliver is it and
you know the trust portion trust
marketing finance covary
I think this is partially where what
it's easy to get mired in individual
parts of marketing there's the people
sort of at the end of the the marketing
timeline where like they make content
there's once I should go and make the
videos and write the articles I guess
I'm we're talking about before that
where it's like the people who decide
like how does a product research go how
do you talk to your your your potential
is not customers in this case about
potential users and what like what does
that look like for marketing to that
kind of a group well you would still
need somebody with a fairly decent
marketing background to figure out sort
of what that looks like marketing for
game B not B I know and then that will
hopefully help paint a picture of what
it looks like for somebody who's gonna
build content for a game B project and
there probably will be some overlap with
the gaming skills but it will be a new a
new beast because its marketing but not
as as money based just know we just want
attention and for it to be with and sort
of this umbrella talking about these
sort of you know goals and these the
word of this gave you that's why
I have a question for y'all sure do you
find yourself using the technology that
you're developing like on a daily basis
or on a weekly basis I mean I would if
it existed I'm not sure like you mean
Fulton so in my case if I'm making WIC
election do you mean do I use that or do
I use like so you use the theory of it
like you actually I mean the see because
this is how I went about my projects is
that you know the concept is based on
having a networking platform where
people update their own information and
and it processed the algorithm processes
all that information and so on makes an
output but before I put in a lot of
money at the software I was like the
system came about because it was solving
a problem for me at least for me and
people like me of being able to organize
my thinking a certain way and so I was
you know that the project came out of
solving a problem that I was working
with regularly so and so you know before
I even built it I was you know the
platform that I have that started out as
to PDF documents and many in-person
meetings with you know with lots of
different people and just yeah just
applying the algorithm and using the
algorithm manually and I mean I knew I
was gonna spend no matter what the
outcome of that would have been I still
wanted to spend the money on you know on
the networking platform just because I
wanted to see it it's even if I was the
only one using it I still just wanted to
do it I wanted to be able to come
through on a commitment on a vision that
I had so just to test it and but but
yeah but so we still had meetings we
still used to celebrate them and to
organize information with various other
people
I'm just wondering if you are working on
projects where you can do that where
you're actually using the theory at
least you know if you don't have the
specific tools that you know the flashy
stuff that you really want to have none
of the open-source software starts with
I need something I need a tool and no
one was kind enough to write it for me
yet so I have to do it and my case is
very senior the project I am trying to
bring to life because I wanted to have
something and now existing software
could provide this functionality so I
started just writing with myself and I
hope it's about to start getting used I
think we can reasonably say that we're
trying to do that for together tech
itself with the together text sort of
that the prototype thing personally for
wiki election know is there's a long gap
to bridge in between where it stands now
and sort of the existing tools in that
space and where it me and where it needs
to be to actually be useful and actually
be able to solve problems but I agree
yeah where possible usually definitely
sort of see real world you said of it
and start to you know hopefully move
that prototype or that did in the head
because that's where a lot of the actual
learning comes from it's actually trying
to make it and use it and then say oh I
didn't work oh that that but that part
works great let's keep building that out
yeah for me and for a reason score yeah
it's modeling actually kind of how I've
been thinking about debates for a long
time so I've been doing it but after a
certain depth
it becomes unwieldy even on paper and
pen so it took a lot of experimentation
on playing with a tool you know it's
kind of like working on a spreadsheet
and trying to figure out how to do your
finances sometimes it takes a couple
goes in different spreadsheets to get it
to work
I don't know that it would be something
that I would use on a day-to-day basis
but certainly as frequently as I expect
people to use it in the future I
probably will use it but right now I'm
testing it on a larger debate that's
going to have you know several hundred
nodes in it so that would be pretty hard
to manage a spreadsheet oh yeah I'm
losing it I'm just gonna say I searched
and Racing isn't a piece of software it
is a process and a conversation and so
yes I try to do that but it's always
hard it's a lot easier always to find
people who wanted to have the
conversation like the idea Cafe and like
solution raising than it is to find the
people who want to have a conversation
about a conversation or a solution or
anything on solution raising but I'm
very much focused on that and finding
that balance like how do we use this
technology process to a process did we
hear from you on what your kind of
marketing efforts are with your project
no I don't think I got into it well the
marketing just a comment real quick and
what Julie said you know I'm kind of
running into the opposite problem
because I promote what I'm doing with a
lot of people democracy reformers let's
put it that way people who are
interested in changing fixing democracy
whether that's I don't know all kinds of
things and so so these people want to
make democracy better right and and so
what our system has already done that
it's it's already it already is a better
system of democracy and so like here you
know this is a better environment in
which you can actually do democracy and
that's where I find like that people
that's where a lot of the people who
want the better democracy that's where
they run away because that's where they
realize don't they don't actually know
what to say because they
not ready so it's kind of the opposite
of what Julie says it was saying it's
you know people want to talk about
having the conversation instead of
actually having the conversation and
maybe that's just because of my
marketing you know so and so as far as
you know that kind of relates to the
other point because I have also been I
realized that you know anytime I do a
presentation of our system is that I try
to turn it into a meeting into a
practical application as quickly as
possible because I've came to the
realization that nobody gets it until
they actually use it and so it's it's
not about bringing people it's not about
yes the software those amazing things
but it's not about getting people to use
the software it's about getting people
to the Citizen assembly to start
community discussing ideas and then see
the advantage that people have who use
our technology versus people who don't
so it's been and the citizen's assembly
is a more common term but that kind of
resonates with people like if I tell
people international logic party or
Agora but I mean okay some people
actually hear international logic party
like one in a million people are like
whoa that's so cool but everybody else
like what the hell is with whatever but
so you know so I promote the citizen
assembly it where I try to show people
how the gora gives people the advantage
and then the next level is the
International logic party if they want
to get involved to that level but so
with promotion I was trying to well
because it's not just a political system
but it's also a philosophical system so
a learning and communication tool so
even we don't we're not functioning by
you know having election well we do have
a candidate but like realistically we're
not gonna win this election but the
point is is it's not just about the
politics it's also about that
philosophical learning and communication
so you know even if we just had like two
or three people it's that we're still
gonna have a great meeting we're still
gonna have a great discussion you know
just using this so it's getting people
to see that to see that it scales that
there is value even
the early stage not just at the latter
stage and so I'm promoting these
meetings and I just started spending
some money on I'm promoting it in
certain small countries in the Caribbean
english-speaking especially because you
know the theory is that eventually we'll
be global we want to control every
governments but we it doesn't matter
which government we control for us
because we want people to talk about us
I mean we need to get people to talk
about us and we want the media to start
reporting on us and yeah we could go
after the US first but we could also go
after Grenada first you know which has
only a hundred thousand people and so
but if we have a country it almost kind
of doesn't make a difference which
country we have because now we can
actually start using public funding to
promote our system so as soon as we
actually control one country it's gonna
be a chain reaction so so yeah I am
trying to promote put some money into
into like small island nations and try
to get at least get a community of
people using that maybe won a few seats
in some in some elections and get some
of the reporters there to I'll to start
to write about us
to get more people talking about it and
maybe some of the international
reporters are gonna pick up on that and
they're gonna start writing about that
in their countries and people will our
user base will expand in other countries
so it's not so much yeah even though
it's a political party our main goal is
to increase the user base of the
platform and which will get us more
publicity which will get us more users
which will get us more publicity but I
yeah I am I am trying to kick-start this
with a little bit of money and the thing
is that it doesn't really require that
much money if you well I mean in
comparison like I was looking at
Facebook advertising for Pennsylvania
region versus you know the Caribbean
it's like you know six times more
expensive for
so yeah if your projects if it doesn't
matter where it starts then you know you
might want to study you know starting it
off in a smaller market that's that's
kind of the strategy we'll see how this
goes but you know other advising that
primarily as political tool which is why
I correct well I'm advertising the
citizen assemblies okay so that's one
thing and you said people are running
away as soon as they are expected to put
some effort into as I understand
soul-searching on their own because the
site is about writing down ideas and how
much the ideas in order what they think
and why so that requires effort but that
is not mmm
it's meta political so to speak I think
it's something that needs to happen
prior so being involved in politics
because then once you've done the
sausage you know yourselves better and
you know what and why you think and it
seems to me that you have to target
groups for this thing one as the
citizenship and for people who are
interested in in politics and in
relationships between people and parties
and whatever that's like no mundane
thing and the other people who would
like to be involved in like global sense
making process starting with themselves
so I'm wondering if the two groups are
not confused and if people are coming to
see the site and sign up and then
they're expected to do something they
were not prepared to do when they joined
yeah that's that's a good point I think
there's also
third group it's a group of that has
both of those interests people who wanna
sense-making and who who are interested
in politics and that's so that's an even
smaller market but that's okay you know
it's the thing is that I what I'm
counting on is the retention rate that
people who actually do get involved they
see that there is no going back for them
you know it's just like opening up your
eyes for the first time and actually
seeing you know and like you're not
gonna go back to living in darkness so
so yeah even though that that group
might be small eventually when we
mobilize it around the world then it
will be able to mobilize the next layer
you know maybe the people who are you
know people who are interested in only
one of those things since making for
politics and then it will grow and then
it will mobilize the next layer and and
so I actually do have a question you
know I am curious not to put you on the
spot right here because at Bentley
showed up at our meeting last night and
he dipped out early and then so I mean
this might be valuable feedback for this
I mean I don't know maybe he got
disconnected
maybe it's some other prior appointments
but that's the thing is I find that a
lot of people come to our meetings and
and they leave early maybe before they
get the sense of what we're really doing
you know and and who knows maybe this
might be really informative about my
marketing efforts and what he'll have to
say Bentley would you care to comment on
why he didn't stick around to Leo tell
us we met yeah I can I could comment on
that for I did actually have something
kind of come up but there were I'm not
sure I would have stayed the whole
meeting now
wouldn't you'd mention something and
then if anyone has any like any other
topics feel forget it says Ari and I
could take this offline but since people
may be interested you'd mentioned you
know kind of the expected commitment and
I guess I wasn't sure how long that
meeting was supposed to be so was that
one for the one hour meeting or the two
hour meeting or
one hour and I got mixed up are we I
generally shoot for two hours and I
don't specify what the end time is which
I think helps with making people show up
on time you know I found that maybe it's
got something to do with it but it's
also about saving in space on a
advertisement you know if I say 9:00 to
11:00 or whatever then I don't know it's
just better just to say 9:00
yeah so maybe people like oh I don't
know what time it ends so I should just
show up when it starts you know so maybe
there's something bad but yeah you're
right so it doesn't make it clear about
how long the meetings gonna go although
sometimes we end up talking for three
hours or four oh yeah and people can
always stay longer but I think you know
thinking it was about an hour which I
don't know how I you know even gave no
hint of that but that's a that's a
pretty long kind of time commitment just
to come in and check something out so I
don't think there's much of anything
unless I had unless I knew exactly it
was for me that I would set aside two
hours for you know that's pretty that's
pretty big for me so that was one of the
things I I guess there might be some
other feedback just about kind of the
the speed of the meeting and the intro
because you did spend quite a bit of
time going over the can't remember what
you called it but it's kind of the local
points at the start of the meeting I
don't know if you do that every time or
if that was a regular thing I'm still
worried that's like a new list that I
just developed and yeah I was getting
bored as I was reading it but there's
some opening notes and I know that's
definitely important um so you just we
just need to tighten it down to a
shorter list that would then give people
a concept and then they can go in for
the details if they're like oh I don't
know if I like that I mean look at that
one but like you said a lot of those are
stuff
everyone's gonna agree to so just
tightening that up
a bit at the beginning and then I don't
know like also not it I think it would
be helpful to have the topics kind of
listed out at the beginning of the
meeting now you might lose people
because they may not be interested in
that topic but I think people more
likely to come in rather than just I'm
it's nice to have an open meeting like
so the people can bring up topics so I
don't know maybe have one planned and
and then sometime for an unplanned one
that that that also gives you something
to talk about
each time you're doing a meeting hey
we're going to talk about nuclear power
or something like that might be helpful
I don't know if for me specifically
since I'm working on a tool on rational
decision-making that people are so bad
at putting their reasons and words and I
notice it more because I'm working on a
rational tool that it's very hard to sit
through a verbal meeting now for me yeah
so it may not work for me just because I
really right now kind of need the
structure that my tool provides in order
to have the patience so I may not be a
good target audience for that citizen's
assembly specifically but for the Agora
tool maybe that makes sense yeah it's
your rational decision or decision wait
you say it again you're what's called
reason score but it helps people make
decisions based on evidence and what
kind of decisions are they are they
collective social decisions are
individual decisions both will work in
the system properly collectives better
you can't make an individual decision
but usually people don't have enough
confusion to need a tool for an
individual decision but yeah and do you
so the theory behind not you use that
in often do client
well since it's usually for kind of like
bitter decisions and and that someone
that you're arguing with I haven't found
many people that are willing to actually
argue with me so right now I'm picking a
fight with two sides well I'm not
picking a fight I've asked some people
who are in the breed-specific
legislation to give me feedback on their
debates specifically on a on a on a
Denver pit bull ban that they're talking
about repealing so I'm communicating
with a couple people on that and so I'm
heavily trying to use it but it's hard
the problem is the problem I'm solving
is a hard problem so a tool just makes
it easier it doesn't make it easy or it
makes it possible but not easy so I'm
actually think I need to hire
researchers I'll argue with you let's do
an argument an argument about like which
system is better well so the thing is
that recent score would be a feature of
Agora
so gora has it doesn't it doesn't like
it doesn't overlap it would augment so a
lot of like you have the pecan with the
proposal process and and the people can
can can jump on that stuff like that but
if you have a point within that
decision-making process with it a point
like you have four or five points on
your thing if one of those points was
something under contention like nuclear
power is dangerous then you might then
dive into Reason score to settle the
effect and then you can go back to your
kind of proposal and grouping kind of
thing so I see my tool is really a
feature of other tools so it would fit
in loomio would fit in Adrienne's
project and it might fit in yours as
well you know I was thinking that you
know tools like Gallo are it kind of can
help people decide about ideas with an
Agora so maybe you know your tool also
works that way but
as much as I heard about callo in many
ways it should be interesting to me I
mean it is interesting to me I just
never use it you know and it's it's kind
of uh I call it the Wikipedia of
arguments but I use Wikipedia all the
time for all kinds of information and I
don't you just catch a load to look up
arguments about all kinds of different
things and so callow I think they spent
some considerable amount of money for
advertising and I mean people do talk
about it I'm talking about it other
people talking about it they mention it
somebody else I was just talking to
today was proposed suggesting some other
system and I'm watching this guy give a
presentation I'm like wait a minute this
is just an underdeveloped version of
Callao so I'm like look okay what is
this guy working on so I mean that's
kind of uh you know so when you're
talking about virality of things like
because if it's something like Gallo
it's how do you compare your your
strategies to callo and effectiveness
yeah so and once again this is one
things we're kind of out of the
marketing space so if someone else has
to topic feel free to interrupt us
but if you find this interesting we keep
going recent score is is based on the
same concept of klo which is an argument
map I'm also working with a group called
the canonical debate lab that's working
I'm making an open version of conic ELO
but we started before kiala came about
the problem with kiala is the amount of
effort it takes to get into one of the
debates for you to understand it you
actually have to read every node in the
tree reason score since it has a scoring
system you only have to go as deep as
you want to and the areas that are
important and you can understand the
whole the whole debate by just reading
the score of the top claim or the scores
of them maybe like five for Tim climbs
beneath it so you can then not have to
read whole sections so you can get up to
speed on any piece of information and a
fraction of the time and you can also
find where you contribute information to
the debate and you can also see how that
information
affects the score which then affects the
debate so I started work on this beyond
before kiala is a little concerned when
I saw because it's like Oh someone's
doing this but then I realized that
they're missing the core features cedam
the core differentiator and mine they're
missing their score and reason score
right right yeah but they do use they
both use argument mats that have been
several already met mapping tools or the
last ten or twenty years I think I
categorized like fifteen of them of
which kiella is the most popular and
most recently but so how does the
differences of your tool how do they
will they affect the marketing
strategies that you will employ and you
know the virality of it well since I can
when I'm putting it out there like I'm
saying okay here's this debate I'm not
just saying here here's this debate come
read a thousand little comments in a
tree structure it's more like here's a
score so we're eighty five percent
confident that nuclear power is
dangerous or nuclear power is safe I
think that being simple well and being
of you know kind of a score will give
people something to understand quickly
and come in and if they're curious they
they only have to dig a little bit of
deep so I think it'll be a little bit
easier to share but and then also having
it where people can then come in and
they'll be and since there's a score
they'll be and that they can affect they
can they're incentivize to come in and
effect it so if they don't agree with
that score if they're they completely
disagree with it then they can come in
and change it so I think being something
to where you don't just come in and kind
of put your comment on it but it
disappears in the thousand of comments I
think will give it a little bit of
morality but it's you know it's not
designed to be viral it's designed to
prove them to solve an issue so that
happens to be viral that'd be nice
but it wouldn't if it's not horrible and
if it's as a hard to market as kiala
worse it would still be worth doing it
just may take longer to get a hold
people I think that's one of the
concepts we've been short like we've
been discussing in you know should
probably start at some point was the
what I've been calling the co-op
petition councils where it's projects
that in theory would be competing with
each other in the game a world like for
example what the election had a reason
scorer in theory kind of competing with
each other but because we're not in it
for profit it's not you know a zero-sum
game that gives us the opportunity to
work together to learn from each other
and Bethenny's right that you know if
reason score comes to its end state
there's a good chance that wiki election
will use it as one of the components
that powers it so it's actually good
that we work together instead of in
competition and I don't we haven't
actually done that yet but I think
that's one of the things that we've been
talking about in the game be projects
together tech space is how you take that
kind of a competition and actually start
to work together to say hey we'll learn
from each other still build our you know
our separate projects and then when they
come to their end state hopefully
they're both better for it in theory you
know one will end up winning in the end
but if you use it to sort of build each
other up and and learn from each other
like that's where it becomes an
advantage that gave me has over gaming
yeah and I've been participating in
something that kind of fits that called
I've mentioned it earlier the canonical
debate lab so there's about six debate
projects in they're all coming at it
from different angles and different
concepts and we're arguing or debating
debate but yeah it's very much that kind
of competition community one thing I did
want to mention about because I think
pretty much all of our projects go into
to to dis realm there's a book called
crossing the chasm by Jeffrey Moore that
talks about this sort of a framework for
how to launch really sort of
world-changing technologies like the
something that the world has never seen
the groups that it travels through like
how you sort of get started and how it
the product is geared toward
them and that have moves to the next
group and the next group you have things
I think like there's sort of the
innovators there's the early adopters
there's the late adopters and then V
laggards that sort of shows on the curve
and you actually gear it for each group
so like you wouldn't build it for the
end state for that first group they're
like you're power users so it can be
sort of not as easy to use but it has to
meet their needs and then from their
jumps to the next group and you make
changes there but I've worked for a
number of companies and projects that
have sort of used that as their Bible
when they're launching something that
like has never really been seen so it's
not something that you can be like oh
it's just like that but what there's one
extra feature it's actually saying
there's nothing to compare this to
explaining it to the public is going to
be really difficult so it's about sort
of how to target that and how to
structure it for not gearing it towards
like your end user is that sort of like
in the end everyone for a lot of these
but actually that first subset of your
sort of like technical you're not quite
ad risk-averse any other traits that you
might need to belong to their group then
it takes you through it so I'd recommend
it if you haven't read it it's a pretty
good good good book yeah I'm trying to
remember if I've ever read that one or
if it's just on my list somewhere so I'm
gonna go look it up and that's that's a
really good idea taking notes on on
marketing in general and I think there's
a I don't know me able to explain this I
want to read chasing or crossing the
chasms think that is very pertinent what
what I'm thinking about I'm talking
about but that some of our marketing
problems are that we need to convince
people that the problem exists at all
right that they don't have the same
politics that our politics that the
problem exists and then that our project
is the one to solve it and that's not
necessarily a guarantee sorry
Bentley I'm just gonna say an that the
problem is solvable several of the
things we're working on people just see
is an intractable issue and they don't
even want to put the
brain to it I think that fits actually
yeah I think that fits Oliver but yes so
exactly what you're saying
I there's the extra element of not just
that there is a problem and it can be
solved it's that you as a person can
help solve it what is your action today
why do we need you now yes yes yes yeah
and they're they're pregnant and that
that it's not just that the problem
exists and this is the solution one of
the beautiful things about what we're
doing and working together to create
game be with our projects is that what
just happened
we're Bentley gave the feedback on
participating in it that conversation
takes place a lot more organically in
this kind of space where it's not I'm
trying to sell you something why didn't
you buy it it's like hey I have the
solution to a problem why do you not
agree that there's a problem or do you
not agree this is the way to make it
like there's a parts of marketing where
you want the person to know that you
exist and that you're a solution and
then there's a part to marketing that is
why aren't you sticking around
why aren't you now that you've heard
about it what isn't a solution for you
if you're know if it's not and what
would make it better and why would you
leave if you're leaving that
communication has to be tricked
to some degree out of the customer or
coerced out of the customer and game a
and game B it's all about when we're
making it we're meeting a need for you
so if we're not meeting that need we
want to know why how do we improve it
how do we how do we do it because you
want that and we want that we're on the
same team right we want more information
we don't want you to buy my information
if it's not good I want because the
purpose is that is the main one but yeah
those are just some of my notes on that
note well I'm talking about books on the
other opposite end of the scale there's
a good book called differentiy or die by
Jack trout and it's kind of about if
there's other companies in the space how
do you compete and it's I mean the whole
book is kind of summarized by the the
title you need to have some kind of a
differentiator or your business will die
is the key
and then they go through a bunch of
examples and what horn aren't good
differentiators but that's a pretty good
book to sort of say hey what not just
what is this company doing but how are
they doing it how are they doing it
differently than the other ones and who
should go with them slash why should you
go with them they would agree that our
solution is the correct solution but
they would not be willing to participate
or do something anyway because people
once they get comfortable in one place
even if it's the wrong place oh the
place that is going to stop ten minutes
in like one hour they are still fighting
very hard to just move not sure why the
force of inertia is just like sometimes
sometimes it's overwhelming totally and
not sure how marketing could help do
that it helps with the conversation that
if just like I was talking about with
that link it being the feedback we don't
necessarily have access to that feedback
right I might not know why I don't know
I have inertia but I'm gonna have an
inkling I'm gonna have any well because
it didn't meet this need or just I just
forgot about it it just wasn't in my you
know newsfeed constantly that you can
actually there's more of an invitation
to follow up on those kind of things on
both sides right as a member as somebody
who wants a project to succeed I want to
give that feedback even if they're not
asking for it and as someone who has a
project that I want that feedback and
can ask for it in a more egalitarian way
it's gonna help you to for me to get
these answers not so I can sell you
something worse better later right which
is what most other marketing is tell me
what we did that was too good then I
could roll back on and you're out where
a little way to get more money you know
I gotta tell you listening to this stuff
it just makes me think about how much I
I don't care about this like like if
somebody some people are just too stupid
to understand like what I'm doing that's
fine eventually the culture will absorb
them we'll come back for them later I
think that's a really dangerous thing to
think about as a a project owner I think
they're too stupid as opposed to I'm not
saying it right I'm not telling my story
correctly well let me let me explode the
difference there is there are some there
are a large swath of people that will
never be inch there are a lot of people
that have to focus on their kids and
their job and other stuff and and
honestly fixing democracy is not they're
not up hot enough on Maslow's hierarchy
of needs to that it should care to them
so it's over it's rational for a lot of
people not to care about what we're
doing I mean hopefully if we work we'll
give them the time in the energy to
focus on these things in the future
so yeah that might be a different way to
phrase what you're saying right well so
why should they trust us right like I'm
saying I want to solve these problems
with Ricky Ledet of trust and news and
this and that who-who the hell is Adriel
why should I trust him to solve that
that that problem right because
especially if we're trying to solve
problems in the areas that the problems
were caused by really slick people lying
a lot we have a big uphill battle on
saying ok we're not that kind of person
we're actually counter to them we're
trying to fight against them here's why
you should trust not just my character
right that I am who I say I am and I'm
going to do it but also my competence on
I can do it here's the things I've done
in the past so I'm I'm trustworthy on
both sides on character and competence
so what I was gonna say is that yes
though some people I just I just don't
have the patience to communicate with
some of those people I mean I try but
eventually I'm just like alright right
forget these people but but at the same
time in the process I am finding other
people who do get it and those people
bring with them new sets of skills and
so it's also about making the project
flexible and accommodating and reward
for those new people so that they can
communicate to those people that I
myself cannot access right and to like
the crossing the chasm book that's kind
of the whole emphasis of that book is
you start with the group that will talk
to the next group that will talk to the
next group that will talk to the next
group that's one of the things that it
helps with is because you talk to the
people who are ready and willing you
know and even if they don't necessarily
trust you yet they're like it's low-risk
and it sounds interesting I'll try it
out and then if you fulfill their needs
they talk to the you know slightly the
more risk-averse but still pretty open
you know pretty technical and then
they're connected to the the next group
and so on and so it helps you sort of go
through that is it's hard to like I
still have a hard time explaining work
election to people using words I have to
use a lot of screenshots and this and
that and flowcharts and stuff like that
before they start to get it and my goal
isn't to explain that to everyone it's
to do what you just said is to explain
to someone who can then say oh I get it
and they can explain it to the next
group of people using words and I'm like
oh of course that makes a lot of sense
why didn't I phrase it that way and in
that group talks to the next group and
each time it's being put it's not being
dumbed down it's being put into their
language it's being put into things that
they care about in value
we're like if you don't care about
innovation saying it innovative and new
and game-changing isn't going to to call
them to action we're at the hour mark
wrap it up anyone has any final thoughts
on on marketing in general I liked what
you're talking about and wonder what was
bringing up for me was to market to like
market to the people who this already
solves that a problem right trying to
convince everyone that the problem
exists in the first place is not the
easy fruit it's not the low-hanging
fruit finding people who it's already
the message they're looking for they're
ready and willing to to do what needs to
get done and those are more of our
people anyway and there's a richness
there that we can tap into that gave me
Katniss
early and if anyone else has any closing
statements before me a small one it's
sort of a note on these videos in
general something that I'm trying to
think of how to frame is as I'm
scrolling through Facebook and I see all
these different live streams they all
start with and we're live and or you
don't overlap okay it's time to go and
it's not anything that's a hunk where I
think half the reason to do these is
that they're now on Facebook and ask
people if they happen to see that video
in their feed one of the things I'm
trying to figure out is for both my
videos for wiki election and for this
how do we have the intro be something
that will help people that will say oh
that sounds interesting I want to keep
watching that and it's never going to be
and her lives so I don't have any
solutions yet I just wanted to put that
out there for thought so I'm like how
can we frame it so that if someone is
scrolling and they happen to see the
video how can we get their interest and
what do we put at the end of the meeting
and we are not like I think honestly if
they if they make it to the end we've
already won so it's kind of moved great
points but yet again they were awesome I
just saved everything I just solved it
off um yeah the end is also good because
people will scroll to the end isn't I
was I was standing and wrapping it up
and saying hey if you too long didn't
read we spent an hour talking about
marketing and how it's different in
gaming be and how we are gonna need to
solve that in a meta way and how we're
gonna solve it individually in the
meantime all right goodbye YouTube
goodbye Facebook